Guide to the Corette and Corette Records 1930-1949
Montana Historical Society
Corette and Corette records
1930-1949
Montana Historical Society Archives
MC 60
Corette and Corette (Butte, Mont.)
5 linear feet of shelf space
Corette and Corette was a Butte, Montana, law firm that was owned and operated by John E. Corette, Sr., and his two sons John E. Corette, Jr., and Robert D. Corette. This collection consists of twenty-four volumes of outgoing correspondence (1915-1916, 1930-1949).
Corette and Corette was a Butte, Montana, law firm founded in 1934 by John E. Corette and his son, Robert D. Corette. Another son, John E. Corette, Jr., joined the firm at a later date. In addition to the firm, with its largely corporate clientele (including the Anaconda Copper Mining Company and Montana Power Company), the Corettes were involved in a number of other enterprises; these included the Metals Bank and Trust Company, Butte; the Mayflower Mining Company; the West Mayflower Mining Company; the Capital Laundry Company, Helena; the New Method Laundry Company, Butte; and the C. and F. Teaming and Trucking Company. Corette and Corette was later renamed Corette, Smith and Dean. John Earl Corette was admitted to the Montana Bar on December 5, 1903, and was first associated with the Butte law firm of Forbis and Evans. When John Forbis retired and L.O. Evans became chief counsel for the Anaconda Copper Mining Company in 1914, Corette carried on the practice under his own name. In the early 1900s, Corette was active in the important mining litigation of the region and was considered a specialist in mining law. As the mining litigation decreased, he developed a general business law practice, and he became a successful corporate lawyer. From 1920 until his death, Corette was general counsel in Montana for the Union Pacific Railroad Company, and beginning in 1940, he served as counsel for the Northern Pacific Railway Company in charge of all legal work for that company in western Montana. John E. Corette died on March 19, 1949.
The collection contains 24 letterpress volumes of outgoing correspondence (1915-1916, 1930-1949) of John E. Corette, Sr., John E. Corette, Jr., and Robert D. Corette, as well as the correspondence of the law firm of Corette and Corette. The correspondence reflects the personal and business interests of John E. Corette, Sr., as well as those of the law firm.
Arranged by series. Letterpress books arranged chronologically.
Collection open for research.
Acquisition information available upon request
This collection is indexed under the following headings in the Montana Historical Society Archives catalog. Researchers desiring materials about related topics, persons, or places should search under these terms.
Corette and Corette (Butte, Mont.)
Butte (Mont.)--Commerce; Butte (Mont.)--Industries--Mines and mining; Butte (Mont.)--Politics and government
Banks and banking--Montana--Butte; Copper mines and mining--Montana--Butte; Laundries--Montana--Butte; Mines mineral resources--Montana--Silver Bow County; Ores--Transportation--Montana--Butte; Real estate business--Montana--Butte
Montana; Business, Industry, and Labor; Mines and Mineral Resources
Detailed Description of the Collection
The following section contains a detailed listing of the materials in the collection
- Outgoing Correspondence
  - Letterpress books: John E. Corette, 1915-1916 1930-1931 (Box-folder 1 / 1-2)
  - Letterpress books: John E. Corette, 1931-1932 (Box-folder 2 / 1)
  - Letterpress book, 1932-1933 (Box-folder 2 / 2)
  - Letterpress book, 1932-1933 (Box-folder 3 / 1-2)
  - Letterpress book, 1934-1935 (Box-folder 4 / 1)
  - Letterpress book: Robert D. Corette, 1934-1935 (Box-folder 4 / 2)
  - Letterpress books, 1935-1936 (Box-folder 5 / 1-2)
  - Letterpress books: Robert D. Corette, 1936-1937 (Box-folder 5 / 3)
  - Letterpress books, 1936-1937 (Box-folder 6 / 1-2)
  - Letterpress books, 1937-1938 (Box-folder 7 / 1-2)
  - Letterpress books, 1938-1939 (Box-folder 8 / 1-2)
  - Letterpress books, 1939-1940 (Box-folder 9 / 1-2)
  - Letterpress books, 1940-1943 (Box-folder 10 / 1-2)
  - Letterpress books, 1943-1947 (Box-folder 11 / 1-2)
  - Letterpress book, 1948-1949 (Box-folder 12 / 1)
- Miscellany
  - List of corporations for annual statements, undated (Box-folder 12 / 2)